# **Amelia Wang**

2066615411 · ameliawang35@gmail.com · portfolio: wangamelia.github.io

### Researcher, Digital Content

After 5+ years of leading academic research in Computational Media and Human-Computer Interaction, I currently blend my research expertise with creative storytelling to deliver engaging, socially progressive content that resonates with diverse audiences. My work reflects a deep passion for meaningful communication, prosocial behavior, and making sense of human behavior online.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelance

### Media Researcher, Script and Content Assistant 10/2024 - Present

- Conducting in-depth research on trending topics across popular culture to produce credible and engaging material for long-form digital commentary. Maintaining a curated list of potential video topics custom to creator's channel and goals.
- Collaborating with main talent to enhance their vision and foster meaningful and progressive conversations for their digital audience.
   Contributing to video scripts by ensuring jokes and discussions were balanced, informed, and culturally sensitive while assisting in writing bit ideas and jokes that were featured in final uploads.

### Brand Designer 05/2024 - Present

- Collaborated with Vuemen CEO to develop a unique and memorable logo that effectively communicates the company's value proposition, brand identity, and values. Currently designing custom logos to help illustrate the product's development process.
- Utilized strong creative skills and proficiency in Adobe Illustrator to create multiple logo concepts, iterating based on client feedback to arrive at a final design that met all objectives.

### Tech4 Good Lab, University Of California Santa Cruz · 08/2022 - 05/2024

### Research Assistant

- Led studies using remote interviews, surveys, and qualitative analysis, generating actionable insights and design recommendations for university and community collaborative partnerships. Planned and executed on timelines across multiple teams
- Managed and mentored 25 junior researchers, overseeing various UX projects, and taught UX methodology from recruitment to analyzing data to presenting findings, leading to high-impact research findings and successful study execution.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Master's Of Science In Computational Media

University Of California Santa Cruz, California, USA 09/2020 - 03/2024

Involved and adaptable teaching assistant for various engineering and design classes:

TIM 175 Business Strategy/Information Systems

CMPM 177 Creative
Strategies for Designing
Interactive Media
CMPM 178 HumanCentered Design Research
CMPM 115 Lead by Design:
Experiential Learning
Collaborative
CMPM 80J Games as
Technical Culture

# Bs In Human Centered Design & Engineering

University Of Washington Seattle, Washington, USA 09/2016 - 06/2020

#### **SKILLS**

Chatbot, coaching and mentorship,
Communication skills,
Ethnography, HumanCentered Design, JavaScript,
Leadership, Python,
Qualitative Research,

### Robust.ai · San Carlos, CA · 08/2022 - 11/2022 UX Research Contract

- Worked directly under the director of research and head of product, applying interviewing, ethnography, and observational techniques to consult clients, inform research directions, and guide product design
- Enhanced user experience and satisfaction by applying UX research methods to improve external validity on in-house studies, inform business product design, and drive strategic decisions.

### User Empowerment Lab, University of Washington · Seattle · 06/2019 - 09/2020

### **Research Assistant**

 Conducted and analyzed participant studies using interviews, WoZ, and qualitative analysis to examine social effects of new software voice interfaces on children, pulling from behavioral science and cognitive science informing user-centric design decisions

### Prosocial Computing Lab, University Of Washington · Seattle · 04/2017 - 06/2020

### **Research Assistant**

- Helped to design, execute, and analyze participant interviews on-site at local hospital, joint project w/Prof. Andrea Hartzler of University of Washington Biomedical Informatics for a publication on the usability of hospital emergency room chatbot designs. Handled scheduling and compensation for participants
- Designed and analyzed study of eye-tracking and webpage behavior, constructed local database for quantitative data which led to more user data points.

## University of Washington Marketing and Communications · Seattle · 09/2018 - 06/2019

#### **UX Web Intern**

- Thrived in collaborative environment with cross-functional marketing team to consult and improve content across the university's websites on an interdisciplinary team with developers, designers, and content strategists.
- Conducted user research to draw insights and make improvements on web campaigns, programs, and communications. Documented best practices and suggestions

# Computing Research Association, University Of Iowa · Iowa City, Iowa · 06/2018 - 08/2018

#### **Visiting Research Assistant**

- HCI/Accessibility research advised by Prof. Kyle Rector in the Computer Science dept. at the University of Iowa as part of CRA's Distributed Research Experience for Undergrads (DREU)
- Qualitatively coded videos, transcribed and analysed interviews on inclusive design for blind users in Virtual Reality. Published with Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) 2019.

recruitment strategies, Research, Sociotechnical System, Teamwork, User-Centered Design, User Interface Design, User Research, Virtual Reality

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Can I Talk to You about Your Social Needs? Understanding Efficiency and Engagement in the Design of Chat-based Surveys (Honourable Mention)

Conversational User Interfaces (CUI) 2021

Rafal Kocielnik, Raina Langevin, James S. George, Shota Akenaga, Amelia Wang, Darwin P. Jones, Alexander Argyle, Callan Fockele, Layla Anderson, Dennis T. Hsieh, Kabir Yadav, Herbert Duber, Gary Hsieh, and Andrea L. Hartzler

### Can Conversational Agents Change the Way Children Talk to People?

International Design Conference (IDC) 2021.

Alexis Hiniker, Amelia Wang, Jonathan Tran, Mingrui Ray Zhang, Jenny Radesky, Kiley Sobel, and Sungsoo Ray Hong

### Virtual Showdown: An Accessible Virtual Reality Game with Scaffolds for Youth with Visual Impairments

CHI 2019

Ryan Wedoff, Lindsay Ball, Amelia Wang, Yi Xuan Khoo, Lauren Lieberman, & Kyle K Rector